let's look at the solution to our memory
refresh quiz we have a memory with 4,096
rows and this many columns it needs to
be refreshed every 500 microc and this
is a read timing where these two steps
and this one overlap so basically it
takes us 4 +
10 plus either 11 or 2 + 4 Nan seconds
before we complete one read and can
proceed with the next one
because 2 + 4 is 6 and 11 nond is longer
that means that really the timing for a
read will be to select the
row so we need to select a row get the
values from the row and then write the
data back during this time the row needs
to remain selected so the new read
really cannot begin until 4 + 10 + 11
NCS into it so the read takes 25
NS and that means we could be doing 40
million reads per second if all we had
to do is do reads and this is where it
becomes tricky because during a second
we need to do a number of refreshes the
refresh period is 500 microc seconds so
the number of refreshes we have to do is
2,000 times per second we need to do a
refresh of each of the rows to do that
the row needs to be selected we need to
get the bit value and write it back so
it takes the same time to do a refresh
of the row as it takes to do a read
meanwhile our memory cannot be doing the
read so really we are spending 2,000 *
496 time 25 NS on refreshes but because
they have the same timing as reads we
can just compute how many refreshes we
have per second and we end up with 8.1
192 million refreshes per second and
that means that we cannot do all 40
million reads pretty much out of these
really this was assuming that we don't
do refreshes so because we have to do
eight and change million refreshes we
have that many less reads that we can do
so the overall result here is the
difference between the two that's how
many reads do we have left after we have
spent time on eight and change million
refreshes so the final answer here is
the difference between these which is 31
mil
88,000 reads per second so again without
refreshes we would be able to do 40
million but because refreshes need to
happen we only have this many reads left
in a second